The moment you start charging people for some product or service,
في اللحظة التي تبدأ فيها فرض رسوم على الأشخاص مقابل بعض المنتجات أو الخدمات،
you've started a business.
بدأت نشاطك التجاري.
You might be mowing the neighbor's lawn or maybe picking up stuff at yard sales and
ربما كنت القص العشب الجار أو ربما التقاط الاشياء في ساحة المبيعات
listing it on eBay.
وإدراجها على موقع ئي باي.
>> On the other hand, you might have bigger ambitions and
>> من ناحية أخرى، قد
be launching your own app on the Apple App Store or Google Marketplace.
تكون لديك طموحات أكبر وتقوم بتشغيل تطبيقك الخاص على Apple App Store أو Google Marketplace.
>> Regardless of your choice, you have already become an entrepreneur.
>> بغض النظر عن اختيارك، فقد أصبحت بالفعل رائد أعمال.
And that has some interesting implications for
وهذا له بعض الآثار المثيرة للاهتمام على
your personal financial planning and taxes.
التخطيط المالي الشخصي والضرائب.
So, here's your first key tip.
لذا، إليك نصيحة مفتاحك الأولى.
>> If you're going to be a business person,
>> إذا كنت تريد أن تكون رجل أعمال،
you will need to establish relationships with professionals you can trust.
سوف تحتاج إلى إقامة علاقات مع المهنيين الذين يمكنك الوثوق بهم.
At a minimum, you will need a banker, an insurance agent,
كحد أدنى، سوف تحتاج إلى مصرفي، وكيل تأمين،
an accountant, and a lawyer.
محاسب، ومحامي.
But don't just choose the one down the street.
لكن لا تختاري الشخص الذي في الشارع
Or the first one you find when you Google slick lawyer dude.
أو أول واحد تجد عندما كنت جوجل البقعة المحامي المتأنق.
Instead, I recommend you find a business mentor.
بدلا من ذلك، أوصي لك العثور على معلمة الأعمال.
Preferably an older person who knows the ropes and
ويفضل أن يكون الشخص الأكبر سنا الذي يعرف الحبل
has some connections in your field or your community.
ولديه بعض الاتصالات في مجال عملك أو مجتمعك.
Who can introduce you to the network.
الذين يمكن أن أعرض لكم على الشبكة.
You might even consider going to the local chamber of commerce and
قد تفكر حتى في الذهاب إلى غرفة التجارة المحلية
introducing yourself.
وتقديم نفسك.
Regardless, always be alert to incompetence and the scam artists.
بغض النظر، يكون دائما في حالة تأهب لعدم الكفاءة والفنانين احتيال.
Now, as to why you need the help of these professionals.
الآن، لماذا تحتاج إلى مساعدة من هؤلاء المهنيين.
Let's work our way to some of the hurdles you're gonna have to jump over and
لنعمل طريقنا إلى بعض العقبات التي ستضطر للقفز عليها
start with the whole issue of liabilities.
ونبدأ بمشكلة المسؤوليات
When you start any business activity, there's always the possibility that what
عندما تبدأ أي نشاط تجاري، هناك دائمًا احتمال أن يؤدي ما
you're doing or how you do it will either offend someone or fail to satisfy them.
تفعله أو كيفية القيام به إلى الإساءة إلى شخص ما أو الفشل في إرضائه.
Justifiably or not, they may seek legal recourse, you could be sued.
بشكل مبرر أو لا، قد يلتمسون اللجوء القانوني، ويمكن مقاضاتك.
When I say you, I mean you.
عندما أقول لك، أعني أنت.
And this kind of liability can impact your personal finances in a huge way.
وهذا النوع من المسؤولية يمكن أن يؤثر على أموالك الشخصية بطريقة ضخمة.
As to how to assess your liability, it's a truism that all businesses can generate
أما بالنسبة لكيفية تقييم مسؤوليتك، فمن البديهي أن جميع الشركات يمكن أن تولد
some liability, but it's the nature
بعض المسؤولية، ولكن
of your business that ultimately defines how much actual risk is involved.
طبيعة عملك هي التي تحدد في نهاية المطاف مقدار المخاطر الفعلية التي تنطوي عليها.
On one hand, if you launch a scrapbooking business,
من ناحية، إذا قمت بإطلاق مشروع سكرابوكينغ،
your biggest fear might be that one of your clients will suffer a paper cut.
قد يكون أكبر خوفك أن أحد عملائك سيعاني من قطع الورق.
Not a lot of risk there.
ليس هناك الكثير من المخاطرة
On the other hand, if you start up a document delivery service,
من ناحية أخرى، إذا بدأت خدمة تسليم الوثائق،
you could actually injure someone in a car accident
يمكنك فعلا إصابة شخص ما في حادث سيارة
rushing somewhere to deliver that key document.
التسرع في مكان ما لتسليم تلك الوثيقة الرئيسية.
Just because there's more risk doesn't mean you shouldn't pursue
فقط لأن هناك المزيد من المخاطر لا يعني أنه لا يجب عليك متابعة
the delivery business.
أعمال التوصيل
It just means you must be aware of the liability you're creating and
وهذا يعني فقط أنه يجب أن تكون على بينة من المسؤولية التي تقوم بإنشائها
consider ways you can reduce it and to limit your personal exposure.
والنظر في الطرق التي يمكنك الحد منها والحد من التعرض الشخصي الخاص بك.
That's where both your accountant and your lawyer can be useful.
هذا هو المكان الذي يمكن أن يكون فيه كل من محاسبك ومحاميك مفيدين.
Of course, the obvious way to reduce your risk in the delivery business is to
وبطبيعة الحال، فإن الطريقة الواضحة للحد من المخاطر الخاصة بك في أعمال التسليم هي
drive carefully.
القيادة بعناية.
And it's always a good idea for any business owner to establish a culture of
وانها دائما فكرة جيدة لأي صاحب عمل لإرساء ثقافة
safety and to institute procedures that will reduce accidents.
السلامة ووضع الإجراءات التي من شأنها أن تقلل من الحوادث.
However, driving the speed limit and
ومع ذلك، فإن قيادة الحد الأقصى للسرعة
stopping at every red light will not prevent every accident.
والتوقف عند كل ضوء أحمر لن يمنع كل حادث.
And even if the other person causes the crash,
وحتى لو تسبب الشخص الآخر في الحادث،
a court could still easily find you at least partially responsible.
المحكمة يمكن أن تجد بسهولة لك على الأقل مسؤولة جزئيا.
Now here's another caution flag.
الآن هنا علم تحذير آخر.
You could also be liable if your product or
كما يمكن أن تكون مسؤولاً إذا كان منتجك أو
service doesn't live up to the customer's expectations.
خدمتك لا يرقى إلى مستوى توقعات العميل.
Moreover that liability could exceed the cost of the good or
وعلاوة على ذلك، يمكن أن تتجاوز هذه المسؤولية تكلفة السلعة أو
service you're actually providing.
الخدمة التي تقدمها بالفعل.
Just imagine you're delivering an important cashier's check for
فقط تخيل أنك تقوم بتسليم شيك أمين صندوق مهم من أجل
a big big deal, and you get caught in traffic.
صفقة كبيرة، و يتم القبض عليك في حركة المرور.
Unfortunately that delay means you don't get the check to where it needs to be on
لسوء الحظ هذا التأخير يعني أنك لا تحصل على
time, and your client's important business deal blows up.
الشيك إلى حيث يجب أن يكون في الوقت المحدد، وصفقة عمل العميل الهامة تنفجر.
The next thing you know, the person who hired you is coming after you for
الشيء التالي الذي تعرفه، الشخص الذي استأجرك سيلاحقك من أجل
the million bucks she lost, not just the $20 bucks she paid you for your service.
المليون دولار التي فقدتها ليس فقط الـ 20 دولار التي دفعتها لك مقابل خدمتك
Now there are several things you can do to make sure you don't spend the rest of your
الآن هناك العديد من الأشياء التي يمكنك القيام بها للتأكد من أنك لا تقضي بقية
life paying for the consequences of one bad day.
حياتك تدفع ثمن عواقب يوم واحد سيء.
One is choosing the right legal form for your business,
واحد هو اختيار النموذج القانوني الصحيح لعملك،
which we'll be discussing shortly.
والذي سنناقشه قريبا.
Another good idea is to make sure you're properly insured.
فكرة جيدة أخرى هي التأكد من أنك مؤمن بشكل صحيح
I know Alex has already discussed insurance, but
أعلم أن (أليكسس) قد ناقشت التأمين بالفعل، لكن من
it's important that you talk to your insurance agent about your planned
المهم أن تتحدث إلى وكيل التأمين الخاص بك عن
business activity and get coverage before you engage in it.
نشاطك التجاري المخطط والحصول على تغطية قبل أن تشارك فيه.
As my final key tip for this part of the lesson, please make sure you have in
كنصيحة رئيسية أخيرة لهذا الجزء من الدرس، يرجى التأكد من وجود
place the appropriate written agreements with your clients and
الاتفاقيات المكتوبة المناسبة مع
your vendors to make sure your liability is limited to what you expect it to be.
عملائك والبائعين للتأكد من أن مسؤوليتك تقتصر على ما تتوقعه.
>> Roger that, Professor Autry.
>> علم ذلك، أستاذ أوتري.
So, what are we going to tackle in part two of the lesson?
إذن، ما الذي سنعالجه في الجزء الثاني من الدرس؟
>> Here's a clue, and it's a famous quote from conservative president Ronald Reagan.
>> هنا فكرة، وهو اقتباس مشهور من الرئيس المحافظ رونالد ريغان.
I've always felt that the nine most terrifying words in the English language
لطالما شعرت أن التسع كلمات مخيفة في اللغة الإنجليزية
are, I'm from the government and I'm here to help.
هي، أنا من الحكومة وأنا هنا للمساعدة.
>> So we'll be talking about regulations and taxes for a small business then?
>> لذلك سوف نتحدث عن اللوائح والضرائب للشركات الصغيرة ثم؟
>> Exactly.
>> بالضبط.
[MUSIC]
[ موسيقى]